CURRICULUM VITAE

Fullname: Nguyen Tien Loi Date of Birth: August 25th, 1985 Mobile: (+84)389 322 958

E-mail: nguyenloi85@gmail.com

Skype: nguyenloi85 Marital status: Married

Address: 32, 38 Van Phu, Phu La, Ha Dong, Ha

Noi, Vietnam



I am a resourceful programmer. I developed software and website in 11 years with many projects. My products used many programming language, for example: C, C++, Java, PHP, nodejs.... Now I am a web developer. I build website with PHP. I work with customers from Vietnam and foreign country. I'm good at PHP, especially with PHP core, zend framework, laravel and codeigniter.

Skill summary

- PHP, Zend Framework1-2-3/laminas, Codeigniter, Wordpress, laravel, Slim framework, fuelphp
- HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3, LESS, SASS
- Javascript, ajax, jquery, reactjs, vuejs
- Front-end Bootstrap, Foundation framework, UIKit framework, tailwindcss
- Database: Oracle, mysql, Sql Server, PgSql, noSql
- Nodejs (expressjs, sequelize)
- Java Core
- Delphi
- C/C++ in linux
- Docker, Linux, Unix, AIX, Sun Solaris, Windows

Education:

 2004-2009 Post and Telecommunications Institute of Technology(Hoc vien cong nghe Buu Chinh Vien Thong)in Ha Noi, Vietnam

Degree: Bachelor of Technological Information



Employment History:

Freelancer

Web developer 9/2020 – Now

• I developed, maintained websites with laminas framework, zend framework 2 and 3. I worked in both front-end and back-end of these website.

- I developed, maintained websites with fuelphp for a Japanese customer. I worked in both front-end and back-end of these website.
- I work part time for webvisum GmbH. I developed hyva checkout payment module with reactis for magento 2 for https://www.trotec.com/

GTV

Web developer 10/2019 – 9/2020

- I developed, maintained website with codeigniter, slim framework, nodejs in backend. I sliced psd to html. I worked with css, javascript, jquery, reactjs,for frontend. Here are details:
 + Rebuilt id system. it's a large account gaming system with 20.000 to 30.000 ccu. When you
 - have an account in this id system, you can play all GTV game. The game may be a game online or a game in GTV plus. GTV plus is a lan game online system. It allows people use play lan game online. User can buy item, vip... in game via this id system. I take part in both front-end and back-end parts.
 - + I maintained, fixed bug for both backend and front end for webiste: gametv.vn. It's a news website. It used codeigniter
 - + I maintained, fixed bug for both backend and front end for some introduction gaming webiste: Slice file photoshop (.psd)to html and make landing pages. They used codeigniter
 - + I reviewed code and rewrote a part of API for game aoe(Age of Empires) ranking system
 - + I maintained and rebuilt report website: tracking.gtv.vn. It contains data for marketing team. It uses nodejs(expressjs, sequelize), reactjs, hightcharts

Thuan Thanh Tech

Team leader 7/2019 – 9/2019

- I managed team to develop an education manage application with laravel. This website application is a bridge between school and parents. School can communicate with parents via website effectively. It also manages almost things which is related to education
- I maintained the old website with drupal 6. This website is about a contact book online

Sutunam

PHP Web Developer

6/2019 - 7/2019

- I learned shell script for using linux and magento 1.x
- I developed 2 modules: blog and images slider for magento 1.

Freelancer

Freelancer Web developer

1/2013 - 6/2019

- I've developed websites as a freelancer for the both Vietnamese and foreign clients. In this
 period of time, I not only fixed many errors but also developed a lot of functions from small to
 important ones for my client in both backend and front end. I worked in a lot of project, from
 small to big, only a part of project to full project. Here is my profile at freelancer.com
 https://www.freelancer.com/u/freshcoffee
- I mainly worked in project used php core, codeigniter(version 2 and 3) and zend framework(both version 1 and 2). But sometimes I joined anothers projects used wordpress, some kind of custom code, unfamiliar platform (blogspot, tumblr...)... when my customer want.
- Here're some my recent projects
 - + I've just upgraded an old website with zend framework 1. It's about a law company in USA. I fixed some bugs related to sending mail system. Moreover, I added some functions for them.
 - + I took part in a project form online service for sparrowlogics with slim framework, zend framework, javascript core, reactjs...
 - + I developed and modified some modules, chat, slideshow, user ... for a german artist's website. He bought a laravel scripts and needed to customize it. It's a website about storing photo.
 - + I developed some module in accounting online system for a german company. (buchhaltungsbutler). It's related to calculate bill online, export to pdf, automatic dunning system... These modules was in zend framework and used motsly javascript/ajax to build front-end. Moreover I coded some wordpress plugin for them.
 - + I took part in upgrading module translation omeka from omeka classic to omekas. Omeka classic use zend framework 1.x. Omekas use zend framework 3.x

Wise Concetti Ltd

Senior Software Developer

2/2012- 12/2012

5/2010 - 2/2012

- I taked part in developing project for a Korea client with SQL IDE(integrated development environment) using delphi and java(java swing, java core...).
- I designed inteface and icon for software
- I joined in the analysis and system design progress of the project.
- I developed many main function of software like visual sql(drap and drop table, view, trigger... in database to generate sql command), auto complete sql, highlight syntax.. for sql command, sofware configuration...
- I were responsible for helping, managing junior developers's work.

Vietsoftware International

Software Engineer

• I taked part in developing projects with the IBM client of my company.

- I developed file upload and download manager software supported for multi OS(AIX, cygwin, linux, sun solaris...). We using wxWidget for building up interface, cUrl for uploadding and downloading file, xerces-c for parsing xml file...
- I also supported for installing library in AIX, linux OS, cygin by hand. I directly downloaded source code of libries above. Next I compiled all libraries with command line(confige, make, make install...). In case, if any libraries were incompactive with the OS, I would have to modify source code of these libraries.
- I supported for changing code from a particular code manager system of IBM to the CVS system.
- I reorganized all codes file in project with multi languages (C/C++, perl, python, shell script...)

Citigo

Junior Web Developer

1/2010 - 4/2010

- I taked part in developing 3 websites used cakephp, codeigniter and wordpress for Australian client.
- The first website used cakephp was about a company with many sub-centres. I supported for senior devoper fixing cross browser (IE, Firefox, Opera...) error about html/css, javascript error, php error.
- The second website used codeigniter was about news website. I supported for senior devoper fixing cross browser (IE, Firefox, Opera...) error about html/css, javascript error, php error. Moreover, I developed some functions in backend, for example: manage users, category, news...
- In the last website used wordpress, I developed a wordpress plugin about text advertisement like google adsense

Onenet

Trainee Web Developer

10/2009 - 12/2009

- My main duty was learning joomla and developing 2 joomla components for a wine company-Avinaa.
- The first one was file system manager in the back-end part. It allowed user to upload and manage image and video.
- The second one was about exporting content in xml format in the front- end part. Afterwards another teammate will use flash to read xml format.
- Modified some joomla modules and components.
- Modified template for website use joomla cms.

iWay Vietnam

Trainee Web Developer

7/2009 - 9/2009

 My main duty was learning drupal and supporting for senior developer with small tasks in large tasks. For example: write some functions with a specific input and output, write a part of a drupal module...

- I modified template for website use drupal cms
- I coded some simple sample modules

Freelancer

No company 5/2009 – 6/2009

 I developed a part of back-end and front-end in a file upload manager project using zend framework 1

• I fixed some errors in some website with php core and javascript.

Additional Information:

Language

Vietnamese - Mother tongue

English - Fluent written and good at spoken

German - Good